# Diandra Drago

17 Otis Street • Apt 301 • Cambridge, MA 02141 • <u>ddrago@mit.edu</u> • (631) 827-4148

## **Profile**

I am a recent MIT Management Science and Marketing Science graduate with two years of market research and data analysis experience. Formal project areas include: re-branding an established company to target new audiences; new product development and customer segmentation, pricing, and marketing; strategic price segmentation on a struggling company's service packages; and research to identify gaps between assumed versus actual product benefit and statistical analysis to quantify significance levels. I also have international business development experience, and am currently following the upcoming launch of a Spanish cloud document management service that I developed product improvements and marketing techniques for. I have an additional four years of client and vender relations experience in the Boston and Cambridge areas, and have planned and managed approximately 50-60 events on behalf of MIT and its student organizations, ranging from 50-5,000 attendees. Detail and service oriented, I also possess extensive mentoring experience and a desire to see others succeed.

#### Education

Massachusetts Institute of Technology, Cambridge, MAFeb. 2012Bachelor of Science Degree in Management Science, Marketing Science ConcentrationGPA 3.6/5.0• MBA Coursework • Spanish Concentration • Computer Science & Robotics Interest

## Longwood High School, Middle Island, NY

Advanced Regents Diploma with Honors

June 2007

Class Rank 3/653

# **Employment**

## Adapting, Valencia, Spain

Technology Marketing Intern

June 2011 - Aug. 2011

- Developed business model for new cloud-based document management system:
  - Analyzed market conditions and competitive landscape
    - Produced sales and marketing plans
  - o Established implementation timeline
  - Proposed product improvements

## MIT Agile Robotics, Cambridge, MA

Undergraduate Researcher

Summer 2009, 2010

- Provided hands-on support to team of 20 in the field and on site (Ft. Belvoir and Ft. Lee) for an autonomous forklift
- Designed and implemented parts using Solidworks and machine shop resources
- Contributed to creation of promotional video of forklift demo

#### MIT Discover Mechanical Engineering Program, Cambridge, MA

Co-Coordinator

Run-Time Staff

June 2009 - Aug. 2009

Aug. 2008

- Worked closely with fellow co-coordinator to develop a revised program
- Coordinated lab tours, off campus trips, meals, daily programming, staff, and final competition for 32 incoming freshman
- Oversaw and led team of 8 mentors and 15 run-time staff members

• Produced and ran programmed events quickly and efficiently

Aided 32 participants with machinery and wiring of soccer playing robot

#### Atlantis Marine World, Riverhead, NY

Gift Shop Associate

July 2003 -Sep. 2006

- Worked to make visitors' day at Atlantis memorable responsible for replenishing floor merchandise and daily upkeep of
  store; ran cash registers for purchases and returns; self directed visual merchandising; assisted school groups and camps
  with finding age and price appropriate souvenirs; suggested lectures, demonstrations and exhibits for visitors
- Took shifts in: the Atlantis Ice Cream Shoppe; as a mascot for birthday parties and special events; and the Atlantis Arcade, where I provided game cards and prizes as well as initiated the repairs of minor mechanical errors with arcade machines

Educator

Aug. 2005 - Aug. 2008

- Staffed exhibits for lectures and demonstrations including: touch tank; interactive salt marsh; penguins; archaeological dig; koi pond; stingray bay
- Prepared daily food for stingray and shark reef lagoon exhibits
- Lifeguarded and safely ran five daily snorkel of up to 75 people/day in tank with tropical fish, sharks, and stingrays

## Longwood Public Library, Middle Island, NY

Adult Department Page

Nov. 2004 - July 2007

- Efficiently shelved books, magazines, and other media types in correct locations
- Foresaw spacing issues and other problems and either corrected for them or alerted manager

**Leadership and Project Management** 

## MIT Fall Career Fair, Cambridge, MA

Week of Logistics Director

June - Oct. 2010

- Worked directly with employers to coordinate hotel, information session, and interview booth logistics for over 350 companies at the largest single-day student-run career fair in the United States, with over 5,000 attendees
- Reserved rooms, ordered food and audio equipment, and staffed 31 information sessions in a single week

## MIT Dormitory Council, Cambridge, MA

Vice President of Residence Exploration (REX)

May 2010 - May 2011

- Coordinated undergraduates living in MIT's 12 Dormitories to run the REX Period for over 1000 incoming freshman
- Compiled 10 page event booklet, acted as official REX liaison between students and MIT Administration

### MIT Orientation Committee, Cambridge, MA

Friday Night Event Committee Co - Chair

June 2010 – Aug. 2010

- Led team of four MIT students and staff members to plan and execute the largest and final off campus orientation event for 1000 freshman
- Identified unique opportunities to introduce freshman to MIT through the New England Aquarium based orientation event and coordinated with various student groups and offices to incorporate them

## MIT Society of Women Engineers, Cambridge, MA

Secretary

Dec. 2010 - Dec. 2011

• Maintained e-mail lists, attendance, and meeting minutes; automated and centralized room reservation process

President

Dec. 2009 - Dec. 2010

- Planned and led bi-monthly meetings for 41 planning board members and 6 executive board members
- Facilitated General Body Meetings for over 100 SWE members; mentored members and oversaw all SWE event planning
- Served as official liaison between MIT SWE, and National/Regional SWE and the corporate world
- Coordinated recruitment process for incoming 40 member planning board

Vice President of Membership and Information

Dec. 2008 - Dec. 2009

• Mentored 11 board members; oversaw development of new MIT SWE website; created MIT SWE alumni database

## MIT SaveTFP, Cambridge, MA

Social Marketer

Dec. 2007 - Dec. 2011

• Fostered community development and promoted mental well-being via weekly large scale events (50-875 people)

Recruitment Coordinator

Sep. 2011 - Dec. 2011

• Marketed group and created member application; coordinated interviews with candidates; coordinated follow – up event shift; notified all candidates of membership decisions

#### **Interests and Skills**

Spoken Languages: Spanish (Conversational), Italian (Basic)

<u>Software</u>: MS Excel, MS Word, MS Powerpoint, iMovie, Solidworks, OMAX Make <u>Programming Languages</u> (Working Knowledge): Matlab, Java (Eclipse IDE), Python

<u>Machining and Electronics</u>: Water Jet, Bandsaw, Milling Machine, Soldering Sports: Ice Hockey; Snowboarding; Badminton; Dance Dance Revolution

Music: Flute; Piano; Composing Music

# **Group Memberships**

Future Business Leaders of America (Treasurer); National Honor Society; National Society of High School Scholars; Tri-M Musical Honor Society (Vice President); Sigma Kappa Sorority – Theta Lamba Chapter; Society of Women Engineers (President, Vice President Membership, Secretary)

## Awards, Certifications, and Training

Composer of the Year (2000); Distinguished Academic Scholar (2002); AP Scholar Award (2006); Peer Mediation Training (2001-2006); Industrial Truck Driving Permit (2009); Society of Women Engineers Scholarship (2011)

## **Volunteer Work**

# Have a Heart Children's Cancer Society, Event Locations on Long Island

Volunteer

2005-2007

2003-2007

- Attended festivals, expositions, and sporting events, informing the public about our cause and fueling donations
- Independently organized and ran a three day February Fundraiser selling Teddy Bear lollipops and Heart Ornaments which resulted in a donation of over 400 dollars to the Have a Heart Children's Cancer Society

## Brookhaven Youth Court, Patchogue, NY

Court Personnel, Youth Court Board Member

• Served as juror, judge, attorney, and clerk for teen – operated court hearing first offense misdemeanor cases for other youths